Welcome back.
مرحبًا بكم مجددًا.
Now it's time to start making some figures.
حان الوقت الآن لإنشاء بعض الرسوم التوضيحية.
In this lesson, I'll teach you how to use software called Tableau
في هذا الدرس، سأعلمكم كيفية استخدام البرنامج الذي يسمى Tableau
to create your visualizations.
في إنشاء المرئيات.
Tableau makes it simple to import data from Excel, a text file, a database and
يسهل برنامج Tableau من استيراد البيانات من ملف Excel وملف نصي وقاعدة بيانات
many other sources.
وغيرها من المصادر الأخرى.
Then you can easily build interactive dashboards.
بعد ذلك يمكنكم بناء لوحات معلومات تفاعلية.
Unlike software such as matplotlib or
بخلاف البرامج الأخرى مثل matplotlib أو d3،
d3, you don't need to know how to program to make awesome plots.
لست بحاجة إلى معرفة البرمجة لتكون قارًا على إنشاء مخططات رائعة.
First, let's hear more from a Tableau pro.
أولًا، دعونا نسمع المزيد من Tableau pro.
&gt;&gt; Hi, I'm here with Trina Chiasson, she is a product manager at Tableau.
&gt;&gt; مرحبًا، أنا هنا مع Trina Chiasson، مديرة المنتج في Tableau.
And today she's going to talk to us about Tableau and give us some demos.
وستتحدث معنا اليوم بشأن برنامج Tableau وتعطينا بعض العروض التقديمية.
So, first, before we start,
لذا، أولًا، قبل أن نبدأ،
can you tell us a little bit about your experience at Tableau?
هل يمكنكِ إخبارنا قليلًا عن تجربتك في برنامج Tableau؟
&gt;&gt; Sure, and thanks for having me.
&gt;&gt; بالتأكيد، وشكرًا على دعوتي.
I've been with Tableau for about a year now,
لقد كنت أستخدم Tableau لمدة عام تقريبًا،
just over a year, and I'm a product manager with Tableau.
أكثر من عام، وأعمل مديرة منتج مع Tableau.
I focus on innovation at the company, which means that I get to work with
أركز على الابتكار في الشركة، مما يعني أنني أعمل مع العديد من الأشخاص
a lot of different people across the organization.
المختلفين على مستوى المؤسسة.
And I came to Tableau from a data analysis background, as well.
وأتيت إلى Tableau بخلفية تحليل البيانات أيضًا.
&gt;&gt; Awesome, cool, so Tableau is software for creating data visualizations.
&gt;&gt; رائع، حسنًا إذًا Tableau هو عبارة عن برنامج لإنشاء عروض البيانات.
So say I already have my data in Excel, and I can make visualizations in Excel,
لذا لنفترض أن لدي بالفعل بيانات في ملف Excel، ويمكنني إنشاء مرئيات في Excel،
so what is it about Tableau that is better than Excel?
إذًا ماذا عن Tableau، هل هو أفضل من Excel؟
Why do I want to use Tableau?
لماذا قد أرغب في استخدام Tableau؟
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a great question.
&gt;&gt; إنه حقًا سؤال رائع.
Excel is an amazing product, it's been around for a very long time.
Excel هو منتج رائع، فهو موجود منذ فترة طويلة.
Actually, it first hit the market, the first version, in 1985.
بالفعل، طرح في الأسواق لأول مرة، إصداره الأول، في 1985.
So it's kind of hard for
لذا يصعب علينا
us to collectively remember what data analysis was like 30 years ago.
أن نتذكر إجمالًا كيف كانت عليه عملية تحليل البيانات منذ 30 عامًا.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; أجل.
&gt;&gt; But it's come a long way since then, and
&gt;&gt; ولكنه قطع شوطًا طويلًا منذ ذلك الحين،
Excel has improved dramatically, too.
وتحسن برنامج Excel تحسنًا مذهلًا.
But Excel is fundamentally designed as a spreadsheet application for
ولكن برنامج Excel صمم باعتباره تطبيق جدول البيانات
holding your data and doing advanced calculations.
للاحتفاظ ببياناتكم وإجراء العمليات الحسابية المتقدمة.
Tableau is designed as an exploratory tool, a way to quickly see and
صُمم Tableau كأداة استكشافية، طريقة لرؤية
understand your data, and do analysis and really move things around,
البيانات وفهمها بسرعة وإجراء تحليلات ونقل الأشياء
change things, iterate and ask deep questions of your data
وتغييرها وتكرارها وطرح أسئلة عميقة عن البيانات.